Fire base ai is the all in one serverless package for accessing the gem mini
And imagine api is directly from your flutter app
To get started to create a project
And the fire bese console and enable
The gemini developer and fire bees ai logic api is next
Add the fire base core and fire base ai packages to your flutter project
then run the flutter fire configure command to connect your flutter app to your fire base project
And your flutter code
Initialize your fire base app
Initialize a model instance by specifying the gem mini
Developer , api provider and the model name
There are different types of models
Generative models for generating content
Live models to string input and output
Using the gem mini live api
And imagine models to access image generation capabilities
Then construct a prompt from a list of content objects
You can include text , images
Videos , audio , and documents
Pass sing the prompt to the models generate content method
And grab the response text one to generate or edit a photo instead
Trout a gemini flash image model
Otherwise known as nano banana
Just make sure to provide a generation config and specify
What kind responses you want back in this case text and images
The rest of the code is mostly the same
Except this time the response contains the inline data parts
Storing the image generate content is great for single turn interactions with the model
But what if you want to maintain a chat history
For multi turn conversations
Use the same model object but called the start chat method
From there you can call send message with the same prompts
And parse the model responses just as before
Except now far base ai logic will maintain your full chat history with the model
For more information on far beyed ai and all the other packages
head to pub dt dev